Well, we come to the start of what has been called the Blue Ribbon event, the men's 100 meters.
And it's fitting that in the first of the heat we should feature a man who really is the second fastest to use
the same bolt in the history of 100 meters Tyson Gay.
The American has been injured from 2010 in operation in 2011 and his hip, but he's back.
He's chosen not to go for the 200, competing the 200 meters in the US trials,
chose to stay with the 100 meters and that's pretty sensible when you've had the surgery.
And he's a man who knows his trade.
It's best of 9.69 in 2009 that he got the injury in 2010, missed 2011 really.
And we've seen him gradually make his way back this year.
And it's good to see him back. It really is.
It's got a fairhold opponent next to him actually in Richard Thompson, trying to down to Bego.
And this crowd will start enjoying these moments. They really will soon when the announcements are made.
Or the start of this 100 meters.
What a crowd.
There's the lineup, Yale, Damon, a side injury, Rodriguez, Thompson Gay,
Fury and Montoya with the first three plus three fastest to the semifinals tomorrow night.
And the athletes will soon be introduced to the crowd.
And there's the Spanish crowd enjoying just the title of men's 100 meters.
There's the San During, bronze medalist in European championships.
10.13 this season, but he is a sub 10 man at his best. That was 2011 last year.
Well, what about Thompson, Richard Thompson, Trinidad, two Olympic silvers from Beijing in 2008?
This season, 9.96.
Now let's wait for the cheer when this man is introduced.
The former World Champion at 1 and 2 has had his problems.
Desk really wants to come back and contend with the big Jamaican threat.
So the men's 100 meters heatwap.
Yale, Singapore, qualified from the prelims this morning.
Damon, Suriname, also a preliminary qualifier.
Side injury, but the regas of Spain, Thompson and Trinidad Tobago, gay of the United States.
Theory of Zembia, on toyer of Columbia.
Heat 1, first three, plus three fastest over the heat to go through to the semifinal tomorrow night.
Well, they got away well.
Certainly Thompson going well, the Spaniard going well.
Rob Rick is at the moment.
Here comes Tyson, gay.
Tyson, gay coming through very strongly.
Thompson in second place in third place, Piri.
And 10.08.
Tyson, gay.
Thompson, second.
And Piri coming through from lane 8 into third place.
No surprises there.
It's got the process underway.
10.08, for Tyson, gay.
Good time considering the headwind of 1.4 meters per second again.
So a good start to his Olympic campaign here.
They look so cold.
I was just worried for a moment.
I thought it might have been limping, but let's look at this from the start.
They are going in lane 7 and the red vested Thompson just inside him.
This was a very strong run here, indeed, by Tyson, gay.
Not especially a quick start, but he gets into his running here.
And this is a very nice demonstration.
It wasn't too difficult, obviously, for him to qualify.
But as I say, I think 10.08 into our headwind.
If you turn it around the other way, that's a sub 10 second time.
And that's excellent sprinting with Piri of Sam Bier doing well.
He used to be based in the Champions in Britain.
Now college in the United States.
10.16 in third place there.
Side in jury, the one slight disappointment.
He was only 4th in 10.28.
Well, here's Heat 2 of the men's 100 meters.
The main of Indonesia, Al-Hardi of Oman, Gatlin, USA.
So Villa of Trinidad, Atkins Bahamas, Eddie Gucci of Japan.
Puch of Poland and Andre of Brazil.
So a lot of interest, of course, in Justin Gatlin.
Four-year drag span.
He's back, the man who won the Olympic title eight years ago.
Red John to win the World title, the following season.
And he's back in terrific form this year.
9.18, makes him the third fastest in the world this year.
And he did that, and wins the US Olympic trials.
Here is Rodel Serrillo, a Trinidad in Tobago.
The championship finalist of two-up meters last year.
Well at the 100, he's won the 10.03, flesh and the best in this season.
Atkins is coming back into form.
Derek Atkins, the Antenna Bahamas, who was second in the World Championships in 2007.
A couple of fairly palo years, but 10.09 this year.
And the Grand Prize is best, which is 991.
And the last one, the sort of form, it's all mean that he can qualify from this first round heat.
Five times Japanese champion, Eric Gucci, usually a fast starter.
He's in seven.
On your mark.
He's remain Alhati Gatlin, Serrillo, Atkins, Eric Gucci, Hook and Andre.
He's two, the remains 100 meters.
It's like headwind in the first race.
Gatlin here, former champion in lane four.
Shit.
Gatlin away very well indeed, Serrillo, Atkins, inside in.
But Gatlin now going away from his field.
This is a very impressive demonstration.
It's mighty close for seconds and third behind him.
I don't know why for the coach, he'll be short on that.
Took the podium, he's surprising up there along with Serrillo,
who turned the down in Atkins and Bahamas.
But this was a very impressive run.
Our first sub-ten second run here.
997 on the clock for Gatlin.
He win more beneficial on this occasion.
The plus 4.7 that he ran well away from the field.
Yes, he did, didn't he?
It was a terrific performance.
Look at him, Gawy.
He's very low, comes up very steadily.
And once he gets the afterburners on,
then the rest are left in his wake.
Rondel, Serrillo, Trinidad and Tobago is left way, way behind.
And that is a strange technique, isn't it?
It's almost as if he's floating the feet in front of him.
But he certainly picked a look at this.
Absolutely terrific stuff in the heat.
Just wanted to show his easing down as well.
Well, look with the photograph,
Will Sword out, who was second.
Well, it's proven to be Atkins, 1022, Serrillo, 1023 and Kuch.
Just messing out with 1024, Andrey also, 1026.
So nearly 300s or seconds,
separating those athletes in the other contention.
And to the povo where Roboska of Poland is taken,
a second attempt at 4 meters 50.
Very high carry on that pole,
which means that it's one of her softer ones
that she's spoken to use at these heights.
She twisted as she went over the bar.
She may have heard of stuff, actually.
But shoots that pole up above her head, rocks back,
shoots those legs up, comfortable clearance.
For the pole.
Oh, she caught her head as she came down.
So, you can see.
She's checking with the post,
but she goes here at 4 meters 50.
And Nick, however,
from the Czech Republic, second attempt at 4.50.
Good speed on the run up, nice running action.
High carry the pole, gets it in early there,
rocks back, shoots the legs up,
rotates over the bar,
and that was a very comfortable clearance indeed
at 4 meters 50.
But you'd expect that, I guess,
from a 472 performer this year, in 2012.
Well, the Javlin goes on.
Here's Daphne Skippers of the Netherlands.
Brilliant run, of course, in the two-on-metres,
yes, they showed early.
It's got bit to learn in the Javlin,
youngster, of course.
And she pulls the app.
She's got a bit to learn in terms of transferring the run up.
She has a very short run up.
These will control the Javlin,
but, you know, to convert that run up,
speed to the distance, actually,
turns out to be a best so far, 3663.
Well, meanwhile, this is just in Gatling,
giving a demonstration of power sprinting here,
storming down the track in 9.97 seconds.
Atkins and Cyrillo also going through,
which, and Andre, have to wait to see whether they have a chance
are going through on some next fastest times.
הם straps will do so.
You're going to come?
Thanks, Dave.
Work is doing a bit better.
stead with 4540 already in his
Well he goes in the fourth heat.
It's a greatest rival, Johan Blake in the sixth heat.
Seven heats in all.
A sapapal between them.
Of course we mustn't forget him for the world record holder.
He goes in the 50.
Always the showman, isn't he?
Always the showman.
There's a sapapal as well.
Oh, two Jamaicans.
No, they didn't get that.
Oh, man.
Johan Blake, what a relay team.
We'll admit three of them.
And there is Johan Blake.
And the likes of Nester Carter and Michael Prater and others.
Take your choice.
There's a sapapal.
They will be coming into this arena very shortly.
We're almost ready now for the third heat.
The stadium ready to receive the athletes.
That's Johan Blake.
He's a man of the moment.
Unknown at the moment, but I wonder whether this will be his year.
Unknown is the world champion for goodness sake.
On the world title beaten in a sprint for over a year now.
He lost the power in the Jamaican championships in 2011.
So he's got a formidable record.
I'm just almost ready to introduce the athletes to you.
Lovely shot of the start of this 100 metres.
It's certainly is.
There is the lineup for your who has bossa Hyman, a sack of Lauscus,
Warner Bailey, matey and Sene.
And Ryan Bailey is the man of the moment here in this, the American.
But this is Hyman.
He was also going to best of 9.95 this season.
So let's forget him.
He's replaced Calam Street.
Chance was the came in on his record over 100 metres 9.95.
During the moment, there is Ryan Bailey surprised third place in the American Olympic
cars, but I've watched him so recently.
Looks pretty good.
Is a big fella solid citizen 9.93 this season.
I know the eight person advanced enjoying the Olympic moment clearly.
I just wonder how he will go here.
The first three to go through by right.
On your mark.
Ruhas Bosse Hyman, a sack of Lauscus, Warner, Bailey, matey and Sene.
The big man from America.
Shit.
It isn't going away as well as Warner of Canada.
Warner of Canada going to go to Greenwater.
Hyman Hyman going to go in here.
I'm spending on the side.
Ben is going to take this one and it's going to be very tight for the second place.
I just wonder whether that might be matey.
We'll sort that out in a moment.
It was very, very close.
But that is 9.88.
Wow.
We said watch out for him.
9.88.
And the wind speed plus 1.5 meters per second.
Well indeed, Ryan Bailey.
That is equals his personal best.
Very, very powerful.
The Slayer sprinting from a very powerful man looking at matey there.
Are you right?
Except he was in contention.
Truvix got by Hyman also as well in name four.
Hyman did go but he folds a little bit here.
Didn't look heavy legdom was overstriving a little bit.
And it was matey coming through in a new national record of 10.06.
The head of Warner, the Canadian who got the good start and came back again in the end.
In a very strong way but that's a lovely athlete that really is.
He's come on a lot since he got third place in the American trials.
That any question at all.
Everybody back off.
Thank you.
Enjoy the moments don't they?
I'm just almost ready to introduce the athletes to you.
Lovely shot of the start of this 100 meters.
It's certainly is.
There is the lineup for your row has.
Bossa Hyman, Sakalowskas, Warner, Bailey, matey and Sane.
And Ryan Bailey is the man of the moment here in this the American.
This is Hyman who is also going to best of 9.95 this season.
So let's forget him.
He's replaced Calum Street Johnson as the came in Ireland's record holder.
100 meters.
9.95.
I'm enjoying the moment.
There is Ryan Bailey.
Surprise third place in the American Olympic trials but I've watched him so recently.
Looks pretty good.
He's a big fella.
Solid citizen.
9.93 this season.
I'm 88 close to the basket.
Enjoying the Olympic moment clearly.
I just wonder how he will go here.
The first three to go through by right.
On your mark.
Ruhas Bossa Hyman, Sakalowskas, Warner, Bailey, matey and Sane.
The big man from America.
Shit.
It isn't going away as well as our Warner of Canada.
Warner of Canada going around water.
Hyman Hyman going well and here comes Bailey on the other side.
Bailey is going to take this one and it's going to be buried tight for the second place.
I just wonder whether that might be matey.
We'll sort that out in a moment.
It was very very close but that is 9.88.
Wow.
We said watch out for him.
9.88.
Past his time thus far.
And the wind speed plus 1.5 meters per second.
Well indeed.
Ryan Bailey.
That is equals his personal best.
Very very powerful display of sprinting from a very powerful man looking at me eating the area.
Are you right?
Except he was in contention.
Ruhas Bossa Hyman also is well in name 4.
Hyman did go but he folds a little bit here.
Didn't look heavy legdom was overstriving a little bit.
And it was matey coming through and a new national record of 10.06.
The head of Warner, the Canadian who got the good start and came back again in the end.
In a very strong way but that's a lovely athlete that really is.
He's come on a lot since he got third place in the American trials.
That any question at all.
Everybody back off.
Thank you for your attention.
Enjoy the moments don't they?
I can tell you now looking down to the start of the 100 meters.
There are so many people close to the start of 100 with cameras on the man who will be running in lane 7.
They've noticed he's there but you wait.
The stadium will erupt shortly.
There we have it.
They line up for the first appearance of Usain Bolt and these London Olympic Games.
It goes in lane 7 in Heat 4, the men's 100 meters.
The silver, the Guinea Bissar, the Sao Davidi, the lodges of the Finch snowblows, the Bayley of Antiga, the Sao Lua Britten,
Bolt of Jamaica and he sits shown to the crowd on the screen.
A grotto of Nigeria and Adam of Cameroon.
There he is, the great man, the defending champion, the World Champion of 2009,
the world record that he set then at 9.58 seconds.
I will be just a tour and form the James Jesse Oloholy.
Next to Bolt, the British athlete going in lane 6.
This man, Usain Bolt, who's transcended the sport of athletics to become a world superstar,
one of the best snowmen on the planet going through his usual free race routines.
Usain Bolt in lane 7, first three short ago through.
There's Daniel Bayley of Antiga, 91 man in his own right personal best.
Two sub 10 second runners in this field, Bayley and Bolt.
Bayley of course, 20 companion.
There's Desse Oloho, a Britain who's got a best of 10.09.
The first match in London, where's the Giro?
And now the announcer is saying to the crowd, welcome to the fastest man in this world.
Usain Bolt, Bayley is the world for the great man.
Bayley of Jamaica supports in the crowd.
Usain is usually cool, so.
He is cool as he lives.
On your mark.
Hit four of the men's 100 meters.
The second day of London 2012.
The silver, seul, rogues, Bayley, Desse Oloho, Bolt, a Guero, Adam.
Bayley and four, Bolt, lane 7.
Shit.
Well, he's away and running.
That's all that's out of the way, maybe a bit quicker.
There's a pull up and further back.
And now Bolt, no things over here.
Here he comes, no shuttle at all.
What does your like for Usain Bolt?
10.08, shown on the clock.
The rest of them were fighting hard, Desse Oloho inside him.
Rodgers as a kid, Nevis was there and Bayley.
But they're all in a different league to this man.
Number one, baby, I'll do everything.
Number one.
Here's a seven, the crowd loving.
They really do.
There he is, Usain Bolt has done his work the first morning.
It's back and Paul, he congratulate Bayley, his training companion,
the team who's second to 10-12.
Adam unfortunately pulled up fairly early in the race.
The man from Cameroons.
Desse Oloho had a good run too, but great print.
Came through in the third place with 10.13.
Well, this is the point.
Look at this, he's having a little look, a little jog, a little wonder.
Just moves past, he's absolutely in third gear, isn't he?
Third gear, just a little wonder across the line.
But that's what we'll expect.
It makes 10 seconds, 10.09 looks so easy, just a little look across,
total control, doing as much as he needs to do.
And Usain Bolt, the fastest man on the planet in the history of this planet.
So, Williams of Grenada,
Kim Bember of Congo, Jamili,
a great Britain, Me too, Nigeria, Martini of the Netherlands,
Powell of Jamaica, Gittens of Barbados, and Gassemi of Iran,
on the outside leg.
Well, there he is, Adam Jamili,
the young footballer has never experienced anything quite like this
that is entire life.
It's been years now, loving it, some wonderful moment.
But he is loving the business,
and he is hugely impressive when he won the World Junior Title in Barcelona.
Well, Asapha, what would you do this time?
Asapha, the most prolific, sub-10 second, 100-bit of Spongebob.
87 times in dip-dumbed, 985 this season,
is best, of course, the former World Record at 9.72.
So, Williams,
November, Jamili, Me too, Martini, Powell, Gittens.
On your mark.
Gassemi, first three,
go through to the final by right, tomorrow evening.
Shit.
I know I would go, I told you what, Jamili,
you've got a very good start in D even Sunday.
Asapha, Powell and Jamili is coming through,
guys, from the, Asapha, Powell,
second place, and third place to, to Randy Martina.
But that was a good run, 10-0-4,
for Asapha, Powell,
and a very good run by the World Junior Champion from Great Britain.
In second place, I tell you what,
he's such a good athlete.
What a promise in front of his home crowd too.
10.11 for Jamili, qualified by right.
Well, it's a very special talent, Jamili here.
Asapha, Powell, winning this race, as you'd expect, 10-0-4.
But Jamili, certainly not over-ord by the occasion,
and a very fine sprint indeed.
Only a second year of top sprinting,
but already he's up there,
in contention with the big boys there, with Martina.
Taken a considerable scout there in Martina,
the Dutchman, who's in third place
and also qualifying at 10-20.
Powell, Neely, Martina going through.
Yeah.
Went to the script, as far as Powell was concerned.
I'm going to let her look at him.
I call him the Neely man,
is, you know, when you look at the fact
he was fifth in the last Olympics,
and he really should be much, much better than that.
Of course, a part of the World Record Relay team,
that's for sure.
Well, here is the great man, Johan Blake.
Unbeaten in a sprint final for over a year now,
since the Safapowl beat him in the Jamaican Championship.
Since then, of course, he's gone on when Usain Bolt
full-started to take the World title in De Gu last year,
and he's unbeaten for finals this season.
Here is Antoine Adams of some kids' nevis,
and there's Yamagata of Japan.
Yamagata third in the Japanese Championship, so we're on turn 8.
Yamagata has a very fine sprint relay team.
There's the pool line there.
Hasn't even on air, the molding.
Three down town, the Chinese record holder.
Right at Neely, from the Virginia Championship,
200 meters, the Estonia.
Then Johan Blake, here going in lane 5,
outside in Antoine Adams, is the kids' nevis.
The Ote Yamagata of Japan, Jeremy Baskin,
of Guyana and Peter Emily Azee,
from the World Finals from Nigeria.
That's the line up, that's him.
Johan Blake has to contend with.
He himself going right in the middle line.
Antoine Adams, well, it associates kids' nevis,
of course, with good colleagues, great friends,
small nation, but they've got a whole host
with really top relay runners.
They've got a bronze medal in the world,
Fox Princes.
That's what Adams is, the latest artist of kids' nevis.
Yamagata, which Japanese athlete
will be hoping we can qualify?
What a good chance of doing so.
So to see you mark China.
So it's Armed, Sue, Neat, Blake, Adams.
Yamagata, Baskin and Emily Azee,
in heat six of the seven heats of the men's 100 meters.
Johan Blake, the world champion,
in the center running in late five, which you make in counts.
Shit.
Once again, an excellent start,
A blade, Antoine Adams,
we're going to the Yamagata of Japan.
But now here he comes.
Here's Johan Blake, looking as easy as Johan,
as well.
You're saying don't get easy across the line there.
Yamagata around.
So to did Sue of China, but 10 seconds.
And this is almost a display by the Jamaica,
to see who could look easiest.
Volte of Daisy, so to did Johan Blake.
He did Denise.
He is a talent and he's kept right away from you,
saying, since they had that contest in Jamaican cars,
which you might have seen before.
But he's not going to be able to do it.
He's going to be able to do it.
He will be able to do it.
Yeah.
His first match, it's going to be a contest
in Jamaican cars, which he won.
He won over 100 and 200 meters.
And won that fairly country in 10 seconds.
There was Yamagata coming into second with 1007.
And then Sue in Jan of China, 1019,
for the season's best.
Volte of Daisy on the pass side in the all red,
comes in into third place.
As Yamagata comes past him there,
going through a plate. Another one is a lovely sprinter. Beautiful high hits right on the toes,
easing and easing all the way. Wonderful stuff. I think you can start better than you did there.
It's reasonable from halfway in. Very very good. Very impressive.
Well-drained chambers for Great Britain. Getting his opportunity.
And these championships against Bladman and Test and Bladman have turned it into
Legos and I 86 man set this year so he's in pretty good form indeed. So we shall see how he goes.
Only the first three to go through by right. Just looking at Jimmy Vico of France who's a major
contender. Just to note the Christoph the nature of his compatriot is not running the 100 concentrating on the 200 this year.
Drain chambers have the beautiful finalist in 1991 and 2009.
It's been absolutely current fastest qualifiers have become into the last eight 10.16 and 10.21.
So keep an eye on the placings outside the top three. Drain chambers outside of the
real seedy lanes. There it is. Cobien. Cobbitch. Him Collins is withdrawn. The
that's a shame or about that. Bladman, Trinidad and Tobago Vico of France.
Grazer, Bahamas, Lopez, Federico and chambers. Drain chambers of Great Britain.
Well, Test and Bladman, the Central American and Caribbean champion of 100 meters last year.
The 9.86 this season. The old schools.
Drain chambers. What he survived this is not the Drain chambers we've seen in the past. That's the
last one. Cobien of Aquino Faso. Cobbitch, Coifitch of Mauritius. Then Test and Bladman of Trinidad and Tobago.
Vico, the European Junior Champion last season.
And the 100 meters for France. Grazer, the Bahamas, Lopez of Puerto Rico. He's the
record holder at 100 meters and then Drain chambers nearest the camera on this side.
First three to go through.
Well, Ben and got a good start in the other side. I know some of Trinidad's going well on the
next side and Drain chambers is coming through to take this. Trinidad's gets it.
Vico in second. Peppin in third. 10-0-2. Wow, what do you think about that? The man who
struggles before more sees it. The season's best of 10.25 ends up with 10.02.
Unfortunately for the first time in fact, we're conditions that I tell you when the two
meters per second maximum win is of course. But that was a tremendous run.
Well, it certainly was. Vico, the Frenchman 10-1-1 in second. The season's best for both
of them. And I was going to say it's a shame King Collins didn't compete that empty lane.
More about that in a moment. But certainly chambers on the near side was going well.
So as Fraser for a while then Bledman started to motor. But chambers on the near side.
Look very good in the end. He really did. And Vico just came ahead of Bledman too for the first
three. Now then the fastest losers will not come from this heat because the two fastest
losers were at 10-16 and 10-21. There it is. Well, I mean the time was impressive but just as
impressive was the fact that the chambers that he beat two really good men in Bledman,
particularly and Vico of course was the European silver medalist.
Well his start was good and he really did pick up. His pick up was great in the first 30-40 meters.
And at this stage he was in the lead and he never lost it. That was a big surprise in a way.
We didn't expect that quite that sort of speed from him. Almost to sub 10.
Well, he's been aiming obviously very much at ill and picks. 34 years of age he may be.
But he's still a top sprinter. No question of that. 10-02 brilliant time.
Sadly, of course the even older 36-year-old Kim Collins couldn't take his play.
Yeah, it would have been his fifth Olympics which the point I was going to make and
Kim Collins former world champion couldn't get here not sure why but a very good performance by
Dwayne Chambers. There it is. 10-02. As you may be called, 10-11 and custom Bledman 10-13.
And the fastest losers will come from elsewhere. 10-16 and 10-21. So, Fraser is out of it.
And so those below him obviously.
But a very good performance by Dwayne Chambers. There it is. 10-02. As you may be called, 10-11
and custom Bledman 10-13. And the fastest losers will come from elsewhere.
10-16 and 10-21. So, Fraser is out of it. And so those below him obviously.
Well, it means that the 3GMacon safely through winning their eats.
The 3 Americans were good. The 3 British athletes also look very good.
So, no particularly big surprises. Ryan Bailey though, the fastest of the day.
988. But remember, Blake and Bolt is cruising through.
Just in Boltz not on that first page. But nevertheless, I think it will be eventually.
Top's the second page. That is going to be the business end. The semi-finals are the
business end of the 100 metres. That is when they have really got to run.
And they have really got to go for lanes in the final to get to these seeded lanes
where the real action is. Although it does not always work that way. Having said that,
there are that Sané at 10-21. And at Hyman, they were the 2, 10-16 and 10-21.
Just checking on the two fastest losers.